Web Developer

Rouen Quirino

Phone: 09268780822 **Email:** quirinorouen@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://arsi21.github.io/portfolio **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/rouen-guirino

GitHub: https://github.com/arsi21

PROFILE SUMMARY

A recent Bachelor of Science in Information Technology graduate majoring in web systems technology. With five months of work experience in web development. Committed to continuous learning and staying up-to-date with industry trends and technologies.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology, major in Web Systems Technology Nueva Ecija University of Science and Technology

July 2023

SKILLS

Back-end Development: PHP, Laravel, MySQL, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Front-end Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap

Other Skills: WordPress, Git, RESTful API, JWT, MVC

EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Intern

Alalay sa Kaunlaran Incorporated

January 2023 – May 2023, Onsite Cabanatuan City

- Basic computer troubleshooting.
- Encoding and updating data using company's system.
- Encoding company's report using Excel and PowerPoint.
- Compiling, labeling, sorting, checking, photocopying, stamping, attaching, and searching for different documents.

Web Developer

May 2022 – September 2022, Remote Quezon City

Arao Software Development Services

- Designed and developed dynamic, responsive, and user-friendly interfaces for various websites and systems using HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and PHP.
- Created a custom responsive WordPress website, including custom back-end functionality using PHP programming language for diverse clients.
- Collaborated with a team to ensure the successful delivery of projects within specified timelines.
- Resolved complex technical issues and optimized website performance, receiving positive feedback from clients for delivering high-quality work.
- Completed projects within budget and timeline constraints, demonstrating excellent project management skills.

PROJECTS

ReklamoKo: Streamlined Complaint Reporting and Management System

- Created an innovative system for streamlined reporting and management of complaints within a barangay.
- Developed a user-friendly interface enabling residents to conveniently file complaints via computers or mobile devices.
- Integrated Twilio SMS gateway for sending SMS to the residents.
- Automated the document creation process, improving overall efficiency.
- Leveraged HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and MySQL to deliver a robust solution.

Blog Post Website

- Develop a full-stack web application using Laravel PHP framework.
- Integrate user authentication, allowing users to register, log in, and access protected routes.
- Implemented MySQL as the database to store post information, user details, and comments data.
- Implemented user authentication and authorization for secure access to protected routes.

- Ensured data integrity and optimized database queries for efficient retrieval and manipulation of post and user data.
- Implemented error handling and validation to provide meaningful error messages and improve user experience.

HONORS & AWARDS

Academic Distinction Awardee

2023

Nueva Ecija University of Science and Technology

Academic Excellence Award

2023

Nueva Ecija University of Science and Technology

• In recognition of outstanding academic performance with General Weighted Average of 1.35, during the 2nd Semester of A.Y. 2021-2022.

Academic Excellence Award

2023

Nueva Ecija University of Science and Technology

• In recognition of outstanding academic performance with General Weighted Average of 1.4, during the 1st Semester of A.Y. 2021-2022

CERTIFICATE

Information Technology Specialist (HTML and CSS)

December 2022

Certiport